Some soldiers died because I wished
to protect this village.
I must brace my heart
if I'm going to be a general.
Chojumaru.
I want to offer my gratitude and deepest
apologies for how it all turned out.
No need. I should apologize.
I acted recklessly.
No, you were a big help.
It's just as Fubuki pointed out.
No one realized
that this village was in a vital location.
We'll place guards to protect it
from now on.
What will happen to the orphans?
We'll take them in at Suwa Grand Shrine
for the time being.
They're all grateful to Fubuki and you,
so I don't think they would
have any objections.
Okay.
And since I put you in danger,
I have to come clean about something.
A phase when you can't see… the future?
They're blurry and unclear,
as you may have noticed,
but it's troublesome if I can't see
any visions in an emergency.
Please keep this a secret between us.
The gods hold power only
if there are people who believe in it.
And there are people
who depend on and seek refuge in my power.
That being said, Lord Tokiyuki,
I would like just a little bit of help
to regain my power.
I want you to know, too,
the source of my powers.
There are wonders
that remain in this world
that can't be measured
by military might nor intellect.
THE ELUSIVE
SAMURAI
Eel?
I'll go catch some at the Tenryu River
if it is your command.
What's gotten into you all of a sudden?
Sorry.
I just wanted to eat some suddenly.
Remember, it's a secret
from everyone that I've lost my powers.
Why do you need to eat an eel
in order for your powers to return?
Last time this happened,
I was cured after I ate some eel.
There are many possible ways
my holy power could come back,
so I must learn from the past
and try them one by one.
Eel is Suwa's specialty.
In the winter, they carry plenty of fat,
and the meat is so tender…
I can feel the power
coursing through my veins!
But my holy power hasn't returned.
I guess it wasn't eel.
Alpine leek?
-I just… want to… try some?
-I can smell eel grilling! Where is it?
Okay. I'll forage some
from the back hills.
It's the Buddhist monks'
favorite vegetable
while they train in the mountains.
Its striking aroma has the power
to ward off evil.
But this isn't doing the trick either.
You want to take this rope?
Sure, of course. I don't mind…
Shrine maiden attire?
There's plenty in the shed…
But why would you need such a thing?
Well, I've grown interested
in the clothes of the shrine.
Right.
In Shintoism, both men and women
are equally important.
One particularly important role
is that of the shrine maiden.
Since we have to keep my secret
from the shrine maidens,
we'll perform a ritual with a doll
to regain my holy powers.
A shrine maiden?
No, this is all wrong! It doesn't look
like a shrine maiden at all!
I need to make a shrine maiden!
A shrine maiden!
I did it!
This is weird, right?
Yeah.
He ate a bunch of things
to give him energy.
And built a life-sized doll
of a shrine maiden.
The rope is definitely to tie it up.
My lord.
Your kink… is wild.
There's no way… that our Lord Tokiyuki
has developed
such mature taste at his young age?
You don't get it, Moritaka.
Spoiled brats are more inclined
to grow up to be huge perverts.
Calm down.
Just because our lord is a huge pervert
doesn't mean
it will affect our loyalty to him.
Yeah, that's right. This is all to help
our lord restore the Kamakura shogunate.
No matter how perverse
his shogunate might be!
I agree! As his retainer, I will master
the art of war and perversion.
Yeah!
-He's a pervert for sure.
-We have a good lord.
Yorishige!
What is it? You look pale.
It's not the time to be eating more eel!
My retainers
are completely misunderstanding me
because I'm running
these nonsensical errands for you!
It doesn't have to be such a bad thing.
A slightly enigmatic lord can exude
an inexplicable sense of authority.
They're totally put off!
You come with me! Go talk to everyone
and clear things up!
I don't care about keeping
your holy power a secret!
Hey, hey now.
I have just one more favor to ask of you.
If you walk about four kilometers
from here, you'll see Mount Moriya,
the sacred place where the divine spirits
of Suwa Grand Shrine reside.
Go fetch me water
from the sacred wetland that runs there.
I'll probably be back to normal
in a heartbeat if I drink it.
Then why didn't you say so
in the first place!
I wanted to eat eel and leek!
What am I doing?
I'm just being subjected to
Mr. Yorishige's
perpetually unpredictable moods.
Whether his holy power exists
in the first place is doubtful.
All the power that he's shown
might just be coincidences.
He leads such a large army. There's no
need to rely on some unpredictable power.
Light?
That's… the Kagura Dance
dedicated to the gods.
Am I seeing things? It looks like
she's playing with countless lights.
Big Brother! What brings you here?
I just… came to fetch some water.
What are you doing here, Shizuku?
I was praying with them.
For the accomplishment of your goals.
For the prosperity of Suwa.
And for peace in this world.
With them?
I see.
Father must have wanted to show you
if he told you to come here.
Big Brother.
Crouch down a little.
Close your eyes.
There. Now you should be able to see
them for a little while.
Open your eyes.
What… are… they?
They're Divine Beasts that live
in Suwa's sanctuary.
Not that they lend their power to us,
but if I pray here, they'll protect us.
Hey, if I look closely, I can see Botan!
I think it moved in recently.
I must be dreaming.
I can't believe they exist in our world.
This was the last era
where people coexisted with the divine.
If you saw a monster,
it meant an earthquake would come.
GRAFFITI PROHIBITED
You could also see a tengu flying
around town.
CERTAINLY - NO FUTURE
These types of stories were recorded
as fact in official documents.
SUWA GRAND SHRINE STAFF
MR. S.Y
The divine storm
that sank the Mongolian army?
That was all because of our prayers.
Such matters were seriously claimed
as achievements,
and many shrines received real rewards.
At this time,
prayer was pragmatic public work,
and a vast budget was poured into it.
This is what Father
wanted you to retrieve, isn't it?
There. His holy power
is probably weakened?
Thank you.
I caught a glimpse of the fleeting wonder,
but it was blurry and unclear.
They're a faint existence that don't seem
to have much influence on this world.
Why did Mr. Yorishige show it to me?
And Shizuku,
I don't think I know much about you.
It looks good.
Bring Tadayoshi.
It's time to start envisioning
the future for our country.
Tadayoshi!
You came! Aren't you exhausted from
working hard at the imperial court?
TADAYOSHI ASHIKAGA
I am in perfect physical condition.
TAKAUJI ASHIKAGA'S
YOUNGER BROTHER
You seem well as always, big brother.
I'm going to get straight to business.
I want you to proceed towards
Kamakura and strengthen our defenses.
Is it your usual "intuition"?
Yes!
I have a feeling that the Hojo survivors
will begin a revolt soon.
Your intuition has always been
mostly right ever since we were young.
When we were children,
I spent three whole days
hiding a treasure
and creating a cipher to find it.
Okay, not even Takauji can solve this!
A treasure hunt? That sounds fun!
Okay, I'm gonna start by looking
under the floor in Moronao's room!
Before I gave you the cipher,
you guessed correctly with your intuition.
I made the cipher
so that no one in this household
was supposed to be able to solve it.
Even if I can win with my intuition,
I can't beat your brains.
I bet you already have plans
in that head of yours.
Yes.
I'm currently thinking of about 100
different defense strategies for Kamakura.
Imagine if we, as brothers,
establish control over Kyo and Kamakura.
All the warriors throughout
the land would obey the Ashikaga.
By the way, don't you think that
100 is an overstatement?
Aren't you really
only thinking of about 14?
Is that the sort of thing
you can guess with intuition?
Takauji is charismatic,
intuitive and a master of war.
Tadayoshi is intellectual,
level-headed and logical.
These two were complete opposite
types of geniuses,
but they were very close as brothers.
I know!
Look, Tadayoshi.
I drew a picture of the Buddha again!
The Buddha is wonderful.
I feel calm just looking at him.
Takauji.
I managed to get high-quality
cedar boards made in Kitayama.
I was just thinking that they would be
perfect for the wooden wall of this room.
Oh, yeah?
How about this?
I'll give you the cedar boards for free.
In exchange, could I
have this wonderful picture of the Buddha?
You have an appreciation
for the Buddha too. Go ahead. Take it.
I'm leaving all of Kamakura up to you.
Somebody!
Recently, my brother has surpassed
the level of just having a good intuition…
It's gotten to the point
where I wonder if he is human…
Keep the Buddha and burn everything else.
-Sir.
I can't show my brother's followers
a picture like this.
I wonder if he's realized it himself.
That he only sees the Buddha as prey.
Takauji Ashikaga seized Kamakura,
and Tadayoshi Ashikaga
protects that same Kamakura.
There was less than a year and a half
until the brothers who had risen to power
would clash against Tokiyuki Hojo.
I knew that Shizuku
could see that I was not feeling myself!
Who exactly is she?
And what was that mystical scene?
It's not my place
to tell you about Shizuku.
I'm sure she'll tell you soon enough.
My holy power
is suddenly coming back to me!
I think.
You think?
The Divine Beasts that you saw
were manifested by holy power.
Holy power exists
where human eyes don't reach.
Where human eyes don't reach?
Just like you, Lord Tokiyuki.
In a world with more watchful eyes
and advanced social surveillance,
someone as important
as you could not be a fugitive.
The rogues we battled the other day
are in the same boat.
People like them hold the divine power
to exist for the first time in history
because no one is looking for them.
However, these divine powers
are beginning to deplete.
When the right to own land
was guaranteed through favor or service,
people's attachment
to the land grew stronger,
and the populated areas expanded.
As the human world
becomes more observable,
secret places and the power
that comes from them shrink.
The wonders… cease to be wonders.
Lake Suwa's ice is broken in half!
Our famous location:
the famed God's Crossing at Lake Suwa.
Currently, everyone believes that
Suwa Myojin creates it using holy power.
But the more people lay eyes on it,
I'm sure there will come a day that it
will be explained as a natural phenomenon.
In other words, the stronger humans
become, the weaker the gods will be.
As people begin to only look at reality,
the gods and holy power
will all disappear.
That's how the times change.
Will you disappear one day too…
Mr. Yorishige?
The halo of the gods has completely
recovered! My holy power is eternal!
That's the source of your halo?
What I'm trying to say is--
This is the last time period
where we get to use divine powers!
And your abilities are perfect
for this period.
You're not a god, but just a human.
You should live your life to the fullest.
The playground you stand on
will melt away one day.
Play to your heart's content during this
period of change!
Okay!
Putting that aside.
Mr. Yorishige, be sure to clean up
after all your playing around.
I didn't want to see Lord Yorishige
like this.
I overestimated him…
I can't believe
he was making Lord Tokiyuki
gather tools for his own pleasure.
Whoa!
I don't understand why he would do that
outside where everyone can see.
I don't know. Maybe it's a form of play
only permitted to a god.
It's so intense that he actually looks
like he's having a divine experience.
It seems like holy power has gathered
because Yorishige is free
in an isolated world.
EPISODE 11 (YEAR OF 1334):
SAMURAIS WHO ARE EAGER TO DIE
& AN ELUSIVE SAMURAI
Let's go!